JOSÉ HILTON DA SILVA SANTOS

Front-End and Mobile Web Developer

Teresina - PI +55 (86) 99458-3369 jhilton930@gmail.com github.com/jhiltonsantos linkedin.com/in/hiltonsantos9

SUMMARY

Graduate in Systems Analysis and Development with experience in React and React Native. Focused on creating efficient and responsive user interfaces. Committed to continuous learning and staying updated with relevant technologies. Capable of effectively collaborating in a team and contributing to the success of projects.

EDUCATION

Technologist in Systems Analysis and Development

Instituto Federal do Piauí - Campus Teresina Central, 2019 - 2023

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am seeking a position in the front-end and mobile development field where I can apply and expand my knowledge in React, React Native, Flutter, and other related technologies, contributing to the development of innovative and impactful projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End and Mobile Developer, Fido, 2023 - 2024

- Development of websites in React and mobile applications for Android and iOS using React Native
- Design of UI/UX using Figma
- Conducting unit tests and integrating applications
- Utilizing the Agile Scrum methodology for project management
- Experience in version control using Git

Computer Technician, Instituto Dom Barreto, 2017 - 2023

- Monitoring of academic institution's database using TOTVS RM
- Transmission and recording of online distance learning (EaD) classes

Internship in Administrative Assistant, Eletrobrás Distribuição Piauí, 2015 - 2017

• Communication department

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Dart, Kotlin, Python, and C#
- · Web and Mobile Development: React, React Native, Flutter
- User Interface (UI) Design: Figma and Adobe XD
- Code Versioning: Git
- Project Management Methodology: Scrum

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS AND ACTIVITIES

- React with Typescript *Origamid, 2024*
- Algorithm and Programming Tutoring *IFPI Campus Teresina Central*, 2023
- React Native: Integrating an APP with WEB API *Alura*. 2023
- React Native: Building an APP with Native-Base Alura, 2023
- Python for Data Science: Language and Numpy Alura, 2022
- Data Science: Data Analysis and Visualization Alura, 2022
- Flutter with Web API: Integrating your mobile app *Alura*, 2022
- Flutter: Understanding HTTP communication and using Web API *Alura*, 2022
- Flutter: State Management with Provider *Alura*, 2022
- Flutter: Reactive Programming Streams with BLoC *Alura*, 2022
- Persistence with Flutter: Creating an app with internal storage *Alura*, 2022
- Docker: Creating headache-free containers *Alura*, 2022
- CSS Grid Layout Origamid, 2021

- CSS Flexbox *Origamid, 2021*
- Advanced UI Design *Origamid*, 2021
- UI Design for Beginners Origamid, 2021
- Competitive Programming PROEX - UFPI Campus Min. Petrônio Portella, 2021
- Flutter Advanced Course Clean Architecture With MVVM *Udemy*, 2021
- Software Patterns and Architecture PADIE - IFPR Campus Paranavaí, 2021
- The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart *Udemy*, 2020

PROJECTS

Acompanhar RA

- **Description:** The application utilizes Augmented Reality and the principles of the TEACCH method to assist in the treatment of individuals with Autism Spectrum Disorder. It aims to create an inclusive and structured learning environment, focusing on visual organization, promoting independence, and skill development. Developed for mobile devices, the application utilizes the device's camera to visualize and interact with virtual objects.
- Repository: https://github.com/jhiltonsantos/ACOMPANHAR-RA
- Related Technologies: C#, Unity, AR Foundation

Busca CEP

- **Description:** The app allows users to retrieve location information based on ZIP code, using the ViaCEP API. The data is linked to users, who can also edit their addresses. Additionally, the application includes user authentication, enabling access with credentials provided by the MockAPI.
- **Repository:** https://github.com/jhiltonsantos/buscaCep
- Related Technologies: Typescript, React Native

2Beauty App

- **Description:** A mobile and web application allows salons to register and highlight their main services and differentiators. Users can schedule appointments based on salon analysis and customer reviews. Address data is saved to display a map with nearby salons.
- Repository: https://github.com/jhiltonsantos/two_beauty
- Related Technologies: Dart, Flutter